Alex Njoroge

Nakuru, Kenya | 20100 | sulemanmacharia@gmail.com Github https://github.com/ALEXNJOROG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am experienced in Python lunguage with the Flask framework and JavaScript based programming as well as a background in C++. I also possess a strong skill set in team work and self motivated discipline that can greatly help existing and start-up companies achieve their particular set goals in the shortest time possible.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- 1 .Javascript
- 2.HTML
- 3.CSS
- 4 .React
- 5 .Python

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Task Manager - https://github.com/gkiarie1/Phase2-Group5-Project

This is a web application designed to allow users to create, update, delete and mark tasks as completed.

- Utilized React Js as the framework for building the user interface.
- Implemented Javascript language to handle the client-sided logic.
- Implemented a local JSON server as a lightweight mock rest API for managing our tasks.
- Utilized teamwork skills to successfully collaborate and complete the project in time.

The Playlist - https://github.com/ALEXNJOROG/phase-3-project-music-manager

This is a program crafted to allow connoisseurs of music to organize a list of their favorite songs on the basis of the artists and their particular tracks.

- Implemented python's one to many ORM to enable an artist to have multiple songs.
- Utilized the terminal to prompt the user for input and to enable navigation through the application's menu.
- Utilized the class models to generate a music database for holding the artists and songs the user inputs.
- Implemented SQlite CRUD operations logic to interact with the music database created.

EXPERIENCE

Dundori Pharmaceuticals

Stock Analyst:

Nakuru, Kenya

12/2021 - 11/2022

• Maintained the Stock DataBase for incoming and outgoing products.

Analyzed and compared branch databases to the main database.

Naivasha Law Courts Naivasha, Kenya

Archives Manager:

06/2023 - Present

- Analyze case Files that are candidates for the archived storage on the basis of date.
- Track and record Files movement to and fro the archived storages and update the affected databases.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Nairobi, Kenya

Full Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program

Kenyatta University School Of Law Bachelor's of Law (LLB) Nairobi, Kenya 08/2021

11/2023 - Present

ALEX NJOROGE

CREATIVE DESIGNER

DEAR MR/MS

I am writing a letter of interest in regards to the position in your company. Your company is known for its innovation, professionalism, and results-driven marketing strategy, which is why I am certain I would make a valuable addition to your team. I would be interested in learning more about the company and available opportunities, so I have enclosed my resume for your consideration.

I am confident that my experience in this field will be an asset to your company. As you will see on my resume, I have a proven record of achievements, which will allow me to make major contributions to your company.

I look forward to speaking with you to discuss how my experience and abilities match your needs. I will call you on the day of the week to see what day and time fit your busy schedule. Don't hesitate to contact me at your phone number or contact me by email at your email address should you have any questions. I look forward to speaking with you.



Alex Njoroge